

Laura Bunea

Front-End Dev, kid wrangler, ping pong ninja and has a mean golf drive

laura.r.bunea@gmail.com

917 819 9345

Bio

I like to build beautiful, progressive Web user interfaces and design systems, with a strong focus on responsive design, performance, and accessibility. My family and I relocated from Wellington, New Zealand earlier this year. Since then my 3 year old daughter and I have been on bear hunts around the city, bubble popping in Central Park, bug collecting on the Brooklyn Promenade and catching pet rocks in Prospect Park and much more besides. I have loved exploring New York with my daughter but I also love web development and am keen to start building things again and talking with other adults.

Key skills

- Excellent grasp of CSS architecture at scale (BEM, ITCSS).
- Extensive knowledge of Pattern Libraries, Style guides, Component Libraries.
- Ability to build rich interactions through CSS and progressively enhanced vanilla JavaScript.
- Proficient at working with various templating languages (Jinja2, Django, Twig).
- Experience writing ES6/ES2015 JavaScript, using Node-based tooling (Babel, module bundlers).
- Experience with build tools and pre-/post-processors npm, Gulp, Sass, Webpack, Browserify.
- Version control via Git issue trackers and pull requests.
- Familiarity with PHP, Python, Django and Wagtail CMS.

Employment history

Front-end Developer, Springload, Wellington (5 years)

Nov 2012 - Nov 2017

I built front-end code for responsive websites and applications, helped our front-end team write scalable, maintainable CSS, and ensured that websites were built in an accessible and progressively enhanced manner. Key projects included Xero's internal Customer Support Platform, NZTA(https://www.nzta.govt.nz/), NZ on Air(https://www.nzonair.govt.nz/) and the Kiwibank(https://www.kiwibank.co.nz/) public site, all of which were built with pattern libraries.

Web Developer, Zing Design, Wellington (1 year)

Jan 2012 - Nov 2012

Responsible for building responsive websites, email templates, and WordPress sites. We were a very small team so it was important for me to be on top of new technologies and ideas as the industry developed. This helped me collaborate with our designer to provide better project design concepts.

Education

Double Diploma in Architectural Draughting

Natcoll Design Technology, 2011-2012

Diploma of Web Development

Natcoll Design Technology, 2004-2006

References available on request